{
    "q1": {
                "question": " Which built-in method combines the text of two strings and returns a new string?",
                "options": [
                    "append()",
                    "concat()",
                    "attach()",
                    "None of the above."
                ],
                "answer": "concat()"
            },
    "q2": {
                "question": "Which built-in method returns the string representation of the number's value?",
                "options": [
                    "toValue()",
                    "toNumber()",
                    "toString()",
                    "None of the above."
                ],
                "answer": "toString()"
            },
    "q3": {
                "question": " Which of the following tag represents the header of a section in HTML5?",
                "options": [
                    "section",
                    "article",
                    "aside",
                    "header"
                ],
                "answer": "header"
            },
    "q4": {
                "question": "Which of the following jQuery method removes an attribute from each of the matched elements?",
                "options": [
                    "deleteAttr( name )",
                    "removeAttr( name )",
                    "removeAttribute( name )",
                    "None of the above."
                ],
                "answer": "removeAttr( name )"
            },
    "q5": {
                "question": " Which of the following type of variable takes precedence over other if names are same?",
                "options": [
                    "global variable",
                    "local variable",
                    "Both of the above",
                    "None of the above."
                ],
                "answer": "local variable"
            },
    "q6": {
                "question": "Which built-in method returns the calling string value converted to upper case?",
                "options": [
                    "toUpperCase()",
                    "toUpper()",
                    "changeCase(case)",
                    "None of the above."
                ],
                "answer": "toUpperCase()"
            },
    "q7": {
                "question": "Which of the following attribute is used to group elements?",
                "options": [
                    "item",
                    "itemprop",
                    "itemcheck",
                    "itemgroup"
                ],
                "answer": "item"
            },
    "q8": {
                "question": "Which of the following function of Array object represents the source code of an object?",
                "options": [
                    "toSource()",
                    "splice()",
                    "oString()",
                    "unshift()"
                ],
                "answer": "toSource()"
            },
    "q9": {
                "question": "Which of the following input control is used for input fields that should contain an URL address in Web Form 2.0?",
                "options": [
                    "email",
                    "URL",
                    "number",
                    "range"
                ],
                "answer": "URL"
            },
    "q10": {
                "question": "Which of the following function of String object causes a string to be italic, as if it were in an <i> tag?",
                "options": [
                    "fixed()",
                    "fontcolor()",
                    "fontsize()",
                    "italics()"
                ],
                "answer": "italics()"
            },
    
     "q11": {
                "question": "Which of the following property is used to set the width of an image border?",
                "options": [
                    "border",
                    "height",
                    "width",
                    "moz-opacity"
                ],
                "answer": "border"
            },

     "q12": {
                "question": "Which of the following property serves as shorthand for the marker properties?",
                "options": [
                    "list-style-type",
                    "list-style-position",
                    "list-style-image",
                    "list-style"
                ],
                "answer": "list-style"
            },
     "q13": {
                "question": " Which of the following defines 1% of viewport width?",
                "options": [
                    "px",
                    "vh",
                    "vw",
                    "vmin"
                ],
                "answer": "vw"
            },
     "q14": {
                "question": "Which of the following function of String object returns the index within the calling String object of the last occurrence of the specified value?",
                "options": [
                    "lastIndexOf()",
                    "search()",
                    "substr()",
                    "indexOf()"
                ],
                "answer": "lastIndexOf()"
            },
     "q15": {
                "question": "Which of the following class styles a table with a light gray background to rows while the cursor hovers over them?",
                "options": [
                    "table",
                    "table-striped",
                    "table-bordered",
                    "table-hover"
                ],
                "answer": "table-hover"
            },
     "q16": {
                "question": "Which of the following bootstrap style of button creates a default/ standard button?",
                "options": [
                    "btn",
                    "btn-primary",
                    "btn-success",
                    "btn-info"
                ],
                "answer": "btn"
            },
     "q17": {
                "question": "Which of the following bootstrap style can be applied to button group instead of resizing each button?",
                "options": [
                    "btn-group",
                    "btn-toolbar",
                    "btn-group-lg",
                    "btn-group-vertical"
                ],
                "answer": "btn-group-lg"
            },
      "q18": {
                "question": " Which of the following bootstrap style is used to add standard links to .navbar?",
                "options": [
                    "navbar-link",
                    "link",
                    "form-link",
                    "None of the above"
                ],
                "answer": "navbar-link"
            },
      "q19": {
                "question": "Which of the following jQuery method removes an attribute from each of the matched elements?",
                "options": [
                    "deleteAttr( name )",
                    "removeAttr( name )",
                    "removeAttribute( name )",
                    "None of the above"
                ],
                "answer": "removeAttr( name )"
            },
      "q20": {
                "question": "Which of the following jQuery method filter out elements from a set of matched elements?",
                "options": [
                    "filter( selector )",
                    "setFilter( selector )",
                    "putFilter( selector )",
                    "None of the above."
                ],
                "answer": "filter( selector )"
            },
      "q21": {
                "question": "Which of the following jQuery method returns the outer height (including the border) of an element?",
                "options": [
                    "getCSSHeight( )",
                    "getHeight( )",
                    "outerHeight( [margin] )",
                    "None of the above."
                ],
                "answer": " outerHeight( [margin] )"
            },
      "q22": {
                "question": "Which of the following jQuery method stops the rest of the event handlers from being executed?",
                "options": [
                    "preventDefault( )",
                    "stopImmediatePropagation( )",
                    "stopPropagation( )",
                    "None of the above."
                ],
                "answer": "stopImmediatePropagation( )"
            },
      "q23": {
                "question": "Which feature of the OOPS gives the concept of reusability?",
                "options": [
                    "Abstraction",
                    "Encapsulation",
                    "Inheritance",
                    "None of the above."
                ],
                "answer": "Inheritance"
            },
     "q24": {
                "question": "Choose the option not applicable for the constructor.",
                "options": [
                    "Cannot be called explicitly",
                    "Cannot be overloaded",
                    "Cannot be overridden",
                    "None of the above"
                ],
                "answer": "Cannot be overridden"
            },
    "q25": {
                "question": "Which of the following is not the keyword in C++?",
                "options": [
                    "volatile",
                    "friend",
                    "extends",
                    "this"
                ],
                "answer": "extends"
            },
    "q26": {
                "question": "Minimum number of moves required to solve a Tower of Hanoi puzzle is",
                "options": [
                    "2n^2",
                    "2^(n-1)",
                    "2^n - 1",
                    "2n - 1"
                ],
                "answer": "2^n - 1"
            },
     "q27": {
                "question": "Apriory algorithm analysis does not include −",
                "options": [
                    "Time Complexity",
                    "Space Complexity",
                    "Program Complexity",
                    "None of the above!"
                ],
                "answer": " Program Complexity"
            },
     "q28": {
                "question": "Heap is an example of",
                "options": [
                    "complete binary tree",
                    "spanning tree",
                    "sparse tree",
                    "binary search tree"
                ],
                "answer": "complete binary tree"
            },
      "q29": {
                "question": " Linked list search complexity is",
                "options": [
                    "Ο(1)",
                    "Ο(n)",
                    "Ο(log n)",
                    "Ο(log log n)"
                ],
                "answer": "Ο(n)"
            },
      "q30": {
                "question": " In a min-heap:",
                "options": [
                    "parent nodes have values greater than or equal to their childs",
                    "parent nodes have values less than or equal to their childs",
                    "both statements are true",
                    "both statements are wrong"
                ],
                "answer": "parent nodes have values greater than or equal to their childs"
            },
      "q31": {
                "question": "",
                "options": [
                    "",
                    "",
                    "",
                    ""
                ],
                "answer": ""
            },
      "q32": {
                "question": "",
                "options": [
                    "",
                    "",
                    "",
                    ""
                ],
                "answer": ""
            },
      "q33": {
                "question": "",
                "options": [
                    "",
                    "",
                    "",
                    ""
                ],
                "answer": ""
            },
      "q34": {
                "question": "",
                "options": [
                    "",
                    "",
                    "",
                    ""
                ],
                "answer": ""
            },
      "q35": {
                "question": "",
                "options": [
                    "",
                    "",
                    "",
                    ""
                ],
                "answer": ""
            },
      "q36": {
                "question": "",
                "options": [
                    "",
                    "",
                    "",
                    ""
                ],
                "answer": ""
            },
      "q37": {
                "question": "",
                "options": [
                    "",
                    "",
                    "",
                    ""
                ],
                "answer": ""
            },
      "q38": {
                "question": "",
                "options": [
                    "",
                    "",
                    "",
                    ""
                ],
                "answer": ""
            },
      "q39": {
                "question": "",
                "options": [
                    "",
                    "",
                    "",
                    ""
                ],
                "answer": ""
            },
      "q40": {
                "question": "",
                "options": [
                    "",
                    "",
                    "",
                    ""
                ],
                "answer": ""
            },
      "q41": {
                "question": "",
                "options": [
                    "",
                    "",
                    "",
                    ""
                ],
                "answer": ""
            },
      "q42": {
                "question": "",
                "options": [
                    "",
                    "",
                    "",
                    ""
                ],
                "answer": ""
            },
      "q43": {
                "question": "",
                "options": [
                    "",
                    "",
                    "",
                    ""
                ],
                "answer": ""
            },
      "q44": {
                "question": "",
                "options": [
                    "",
                    "",
                    "",
                    ""
                ],
                "answer": ""
            },
      "q45": {
                "question": "",
                "options": [
                    "",
                    "",
                    "",
                    ""
                ],
                "answer": ""
            },
      "q46": {
                "question": "",
                "options": [
                    "",
                    "",
                    "",
                    ""
                ],
                "answer": ""
            },
      "q47": {
                "question": "",
                "options": [
                    "",
                    "",
                    "",
                    ""
                ],
                "answer": ""
            },
      "q48": {
                "question": "",
                "options": [
                    "",
                    "",
                    "",
                    ""
                ],
                "answer": ""
            },
      "q49": {
                "question": "",
                "options": [
                    "",
                    "",
                    "",
                    ""
                ],
                "answer": ""
            },
      "q50": {
                "question": "",
                "options": [
                    "",
                    "",
                    "",
                    ""
                ],
                "answer": ""
            }

        

}